Large language models are very good at transforming its input to a different format
大语言模型非常善于将其输入转换为不同的格式
such as inputting a piece of text in one language and transforming it or
例如，输入一种语言的文本并将其转换或
translating it to a different language or helping with spelling and grammar corrections
把它翻译成不同的语言，或者帮助进行拼写和语法的修正
So taking as input a piece of text that may not be
因此，将一段可能不符合标准的语法文本作为输入
fully grammatical and helping you to fix that up a bit
并让它帮助你纠正拼写和语法
or even transforming formats such as inputting
或甚至转换格式，如
HTML and outputting JSON
输入HTML和输出JSON
So there's a bunch of applications that I used to write somewhat painfully with
所以，我以前写的一些应用程序有点痛苦，用的是
a bunch of regular expressions that would definitely be much more
一堆正则表达式的应用
simply implemented now with a large language model and a few prompts
现在用一个大语言模型和一些提示语就可以更简单地实现
Yeah, I use ChatGPT to proofread pretty much everything I write these days
是的，我现在用ChatGPT来校对我写的几乎所有东西
So I'm excited to show you some more examples in the notebook now
所以我很高兴现在向你展示Notebook中的一些更多的例子
So first, we'll import openai and also
所以，首先，我们将导入openai，同时
use the same get_completion helper function that we've been using throughout the videos
使用我们在整个视频中一直使用的get_completion辅助函数
The first thing we'll do is a translation task
我们要做的第一件事是一个翻译任务
So large language models are trained on a lot of text from many sources
因此，大语言模型是在许多来源的大量文本上训练出来的
a lot of which is the Internet
其中有很多是互联网
and this is of course in many different languages
这当然是用许多不同的语言
So this imbues the model with the ability to do translation
因此，这使模型具有翻译能力
These models know hundreds of languages to varying degrees of proficiency
这些模型知道数百种语言的不同程度的熟练程度
So we'll go through some examples of how to use this capability
所以我们将通过一些例子来说明如何使用这种能力
So let's start off with something simple
所以，让我们从简单的东西开始
So in this first example
所以在这第一个例子中
the prompt is translate the following English text to Spanish
提示是将以下英文文本翻译成西班牙语
Hi, I would like to order a blender
你好，我想订购一台搅拌机
The response is, Hola
响应是：Hola
me gustaría ordenar una licuadora
me gustaría ordenar una licuadora.
I'm very sorry to all of you Spanish speakers
我对所有讲西班牙语的人感到非常抱歉
I never learned Spanish unfortunately, as you can definitely tell
我从来没有学过西班牙语，很不幸，你肯定能看出来
Let's try another example
让我们尝试另一个例子
So in this example
所以在这个例子中
the prompt is, tell me what language this is
提示是，告诉我这是什么语言
Then this is in French
那么这是用法语说的
combien coûte le lampadaire?
combien coûte le lampadaire?
So let's run this
所以我们来运行这个
The model has identified that this is French
该模型已经识别出这是法语
The model can also do multiple translations at once
该模型还可以一次做多个翻译
So in this example
所以在这个例子中
let's say translate the following text to French and Spanish
让我们说把下面的文字翻译成法语和西班牙语
You know what, let's add another
你知道吗，让我们再加一个
an English pirate
英国海盗
The text is, I want to order a basketball
这段文字是，我想订购一个篮球
So here we have French
所以这里我们有法语
Spanish, and English pirate
西班牙文，和英国海盗
So in some languages
所以在某些语言中
the translation can change depending on
翻译可以改变，取决于
the speaker's relationship to the listener
说话人与听话人的关系
You can also explain this to the language model
你也可以向语言模型解释这一点
and so it will be able to translate accordingly
这样它就能进行相应的翻译
So in this example
所以在这个例子中
we say translate the following text to Spanish in both the formal and informal forms
我们说把下面的文字以正式和非正式的形式翻译成西班牙语
Would you like to order a pillow?
你想订购一个枕头吗？
Also notice here, we're using
还注意到，我们在这里使用了
a different delimiter than these backticks
不同的分隔符，而不是这些双引号
It doesn't really matter as long as it's a clear separation
其实这并不重要，只要它是一个清晰的分隔
So here we have the formal and informal
所以这里我们有正式和非正式
So formal is when you're speaking to someone who's
因此，正式的是当你和某人说话时，他是
maybe senior to you or you're in a professional situation
也许比你高级的人，或者你是在一个专业的情况下
That's when you use a formal tone
这时你要使用正式语气
and then informal is when you're speaking to maybe a group of friends
然后非正式的是当你和一群朋友说话时
I don't actually speak Spanish
我实际上不会说西班牙语
but my dad does and he says that this is correct
但我父亲会，他说这是正确的
So for the next example
因此，对于
we're going to pretend that we're in charge of a multinational e-commerce company
我们要假装自己是一家跨国电子商务公司的负责人
and so the user messages are going to be in all different languages
用户的信息将使用所有不同的语言
and so users are going to be telling us about the IT issues in wide variety of languages
因此，用户将用各种不同的语言告诉我们关于IT的问题
So we need a universal translator
所以我们需要一个通用的翻译器
So first, we'll just paste in a list of user messages in a variety of different languages
因此，首先，我们将粘贴一个各种不同语言的用户信息的列表
Now, we will loop through each of these user messages
现在，我们将循环浏览这些用户信息中的每一条
So for issue in user messages
因此，对于用户信息中的问题
and then I'm going to copy over the slightly longer code block
然后我将复制稍长的代码块
So the first thing we'll do is ask the model
所以我们要做的第一件事是要求模型
to tell us what language the issue is in
告诉我们这个问题是什么语言的
So here's the prompt
所以这里是提示
Then we'll print out the original messages language and the issue
然后，我们将打印出原始信息的语言和问题
and then we'll ask the model to translate it into English and Korean
然后我们将要求模型将其翻译成英语和韩语
So let's run this. So the original message in French
所以让我们运行这个。所以，原始信息是法语
So we have a variety of languages
所以我们有各种语言
and then the model translates them into English and then Korean
然后模型将它们翻译成英语和韩语
You can see here, so the model says
你可以看到这里，所以模型说
this is French
这是法语
So that's because the response from this prompt is going to be, this is French
所以这是因为这个提示的反应将是，这是法语
You could try editing this prompt to say something like
你可以尝试将这个提示编辑成这样的内容
tell me what language this is
告诉我这是什么语言
respond with only one word or don't use a sentence
只用一个词来回答或不用句子
that kind of thing if you wanted this to just be one word
如果你希望这只是一个词的话
or you could ask for it in a JSON format or something like that
或者你可以要求它以JSON格式或类似的东西
which would probably encourage it to not use a whole sentence
这可能会鼓励它不要使用整个句子
So amazing, you've just built a universal translator
因此，令人惊讶的是，你刚刚建立了一个通用翻译器
and also feel free to pause the video and add any other languages you want to try here
也可以随时暂停视频，在这里添加任何你想尝试的其他语言
maybe languages you speak yourself
也许是你自己说的语言
and see how the model does
看看这个模型是怎么做的
So the next thing we're going to dive into is tone transformation
因此，我们接下来要深入研究的是语气转换
Writing can vary based on an intended audience
写作可以根据目标受众而有所不同
the way that I would write an e-mail to a colleague or a professor
我给同事或教授写电子邮件的方式
is obviously going to be quite different to the way I text my younger brother
显然会与我给我弟弟发短信的方式完全不同
So ChatGPT can actually also help produce different tones
所以ChatGPT实际上也可以帮助产生不同的语气
So let's look at some examples
因此，让我们看一些例子
So in this first example
在这第一个例子中
the prompt is, translate the following from slang to a business letter
提示是，将以下内容从俚语翻译成商务信函
Dude, this is Joe
老兄，这是乔
check out the spec on the standing lamp
检查一下这盏落地灯的规格
So let's execute this
因此，让我们来执行这个
As you can see, we have a much more formal business letter
正如你所看到的，我们有一封更正式的商业信函
with a proposal for a standing lamp specification
有一个关于落地灯规格的建议
The next thing that we're going to do is to convert between different formats
我们要做的下一件事是在不同的格式之间进行转换
ChatGPT is very good at translating between different formats such as JSON to HTML
ChatGPT非常善于在不同的格式之间进行转换，如JSON到HTML
XML, all kinds of things, markdown
XML，各种各样的东西，markdown
So in the prompt, we'll describe both the input and the output formats
所以在提示中，我们将描述输入和输出的格式
So here is an example
所以这里有一个例子
So we have this JSON that
所以我们有这样一个JSON
contains a list of restaurant employees with their name and e-mail
它包含一个餐厅员工的名单，包括他们的名字和电子邮件
Then in the prompt
然后在提示中
we're going to ask the model to translate this from JSON to HTML
我们将要求模型将其从JSON翻译成HTML
So the prompt is, translate the following Python dictionary from JSON to
所以提示是，把下面的Python字典从JSON翻译成
HTML with column headers and titles
HTML，包括列头和标题
Then we'll get the response from the model and print it
然后我们将从模型中得到响应并打印出来
So here we have some HTML displaying all of the employee names and e-mails
所以这里我们有一些HTML显示所有的雇员姓名和电子邮件
So now let's see if we can actually view this HTML
那么现在让我们来看看我们是否可以作为
So we're going to use this display function from this Python library
所以我们要使用这个Python库中的这个显示函数
display HTML response
显示 HTML 响应
Here you can see that this is a properly formatted HTML table
在这里你可以看到这是一个正确格式化的HTML表格
The next transformation task we're going to do is spell check and grammar checking
我们要做的下一个转换任务是拼写检查和语法检查
This is a really popular use for ChatGPT
这是ChatGPT的一个非常流行的用途
I highly recommend doing this
我强烈建议这样做
I do this all the time
我一直在做这个
It's especially useful when you're working in a non-native language
当你用非母语工作时，它尤其有用
So here are some examples of some common grammar and spelling problems
因此，这里有一些常见的语法和拼写问题的例子
and how the language model can help address these
以及语言模型如何帮助解决这些问题
So I'm going to paste in a list of sentences that have some grammatical or spelling errors
所以我将粘贴一个有一些语法或拼写错误的句子列表
Then we're going to loop through each of these sentences
然后，我们将循环浏览每一个句子
And
然后
ask the model to proofread these.
让模型进行校对
Proofread and correct. And then we'll use some delimiters.
校对并进行修正。然后我们将使用一些分隔符
And then we will get the response and print it as usual.
然后我们将获取响应并将其打印出来，就像往常一样
And so the model is able to correct all of these grammatical errors
就这样，这个模型能够纠正所有这些语法错误
We could use some of the techniques that we've discussed before
我们可以使用我们之前讨论过的一些技术
So to improve the prompt, we could say proofread and correct the following text
因此，为了改进提示，我们可以说校对和纠正以下文字
And rewrite
并重写
Oh
哦
And rewrite the whole
并重写整个
And rewrite it
并重写
Corrected version
改正后的版本
If you don't find any errors, just say no errors found
如果你没有发现任何错误，就说没有发现错误
Let's try this
让我们来试试这个
So this way we were able to, oh, they're still using quotes here
因此，这种方式我们能够，哦，他们在这里仍然使用引号
But you can imagine you'd be able to find a way with a little bit of
但你可以想象，你能够找到一种方法，用一点点的
iterative prompt development to
迭代提示开发
kind of find a prompt that works more reliably every single time
找到一种更可靠的提示方式，每一次都能正常工作
And so now we'll do another example
因此，现在我们将实现另一个例子
It's always useful to check your text before you post it in a public forum
在你把你的文本发布到公共论坛之前，检查它总是有用的
And so we'll go through an example of checking a review
因此，我们将通过一个检查评论的例子
And so here is a review about a stuffed panda
这里有一个关于毛绒熊猫的评论
And so we're going to ask the model to proofread and correct the review
因此，我们将要求模型校对和纠正评论
Great. So we have this corrected version
很好。所以我们有了这个更正的版本
And one cool thing we can do is find
我们可以做的一件很酷的事情是找到
the kind of differences between our original review and the model's output
我们的原始评论和模型的输出之间的差异
So we're going to use this red lines Python package to do this
所以我们要基于这个Redlines Python包来做这个
And we're going to get the diff between
我们将得到以下的差异
the original text of our review and the model output
我们评论的原文和模型的输出之间的差异
and then display this
然后显示这个
And so here you can see the diff between the original review
所以在这里你可以看到原始评论和模型输出之间的差异
and the model output and the kind of things that have been corrected
和模型输出之间的差异，以及那些已经被纠正的东西
So the prompt that we use was proofread and correct this review
因此，我们使用的提示是校对和纠正这个评论
But you can also make kind of more dramatic changes
但你也可以做一些更戏剧性的改变
kind of changes to tone and that kind of thing
语气的变化，以及诸如此类的事情
So let's try one more thing
因此，让我们再试一试
So in this prompt, we're going to ask the model to proofread and correct
所以在这个提示中，我们将要求模特校对和纠正
the same review, but also make it more compelling and ensure that it
同样的评论，但也要使其更有说服力，并确保其
follows APA style and targets an advanced reader
遵循APA风格，并针对高级读者
And we're also going to ask for the output in markdown format
我们还将要求以Markdown格式输出结果
And so we're using the same text from the original review up here
因此，我们在这里使用原始审查的相同文本
So let's execute this
因此，让我们来执行这个
And here we have a expanded APA style review of the soft Panda
在这里，我们有一个扩展的APA风格的毛绒熊猫的评论
So this is it for the transforming video
因此，这是它的转换视频
Next up, we have expanding where we'll take a shorter prompt
接下来，我们将使用扩写功能，采取较短的提示
and kind of generate a longer, more freeform response from a language model
并从语言模型中产生一个更长、更自由的反应